NAFKOT ALDADA

nafkot.aldada@gmail.com Indianapolis, IN

https://nafki.github.io/Portfilio_project/ linkedin.com/in/nafkot-aldada-674228219

FULL STACK & MULESOFT DEVELOPER

Skilled and knowledgeable Full Stack Developer with experience that includes front end technologies like javascript, TypeScript, react, HTML,CSS, bootstrap and Back-End technologies such as nodejs. Proven ability to apply agile software development methodology to build interactive and user friendly web applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Libraries: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, ActiveMQ, mySQL

Cloud Technologies: Firebase Hosting, Heroku, GitHub

CI/CD: Agile, Scrum, Git

Database: PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MySQL, Relational Databases

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, APIs, JSON, XML, MVC, Responsive web design, Bootstrap, Reactstrap

Web Services: RESTful Testing Tools: Jest

Tools: salesforce, Postman, Anypoint Studio

Platforms: Windows 10,

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Eleven Fifty Academy(July 6, 2021 - October, 2021)

Developed and implemented full stack projects like climate change observer application and Game List Applications. By utilizing CSS,HTML, javaScript and typeScript language skills, I created web pages with interactive user experience. Developed web applications using architectural patterns like model-view-controller(MVC) and representational state transfer (REST). Implemented testing operating systems, various bug fix repairs and committed to git, firebase and deployed to Heroku.

MyVuniversity(January 17, 2019- now)

Configure Mule service flows with various exception handling strategies such as Global Exception, Custom Exception and Choice Exception Strategies. Create an Integration Component with a third party application using Mule ESB. Worked on creating REST web services in Mule, Consumption of REST. Implement interfaces between SAP, Sales Force and REST web-services.

Amazon(December 14, 2020 - now)

Examine, verify, and process customer return items for price deals. Responsible for managing, retrieving, and organizing warehouse deal products. Excellent communication skills to effectively interact with team members

EDUCATION

Eleven Fifty Academy, USA, Indianapolis, IN

➤ 12-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training

myVuniversity, India, Maharashtra

➤ Mulesoft development

Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia, Addis Ababa

➤ Urban Management, Political Science and International Relation